今天有多少人因耶稣而欢喜？
这里有喜乐 是说不出来的喜乐
因为神就在这里
来吧 我们一起唱！
让主的荣耀在我们中间升起
让主的荣耀升起
哦 让我们向君王献上赞美
让它升起来！
今天别让石头替我们呼喊
愿主的荣耀降临在我们身上
愿主的荣耀彰显
愿它兴起
愿我主的平安
愿圣灵的微风吹拂我们
哦 就是那孩子
哦 让我也在这里献上赞美
哦 我们歌唱 齐声颂扬
耶稣值得我们活
献给万王之王
今早 万主之主
让我们的赞美响彻云霄
圣经说 若我们不赞美祂
石头都要呼喊起来
哦 今早别让石头替我们呼喊
祂配得我们所有赞美
哈利路亚
赞美你 Jesus
哦 我们爱你 Lord
哦 我们敬拜你 Lord
哈利路亚
主啊 愿你的名得荣耀
哦 今天早上 我想鼓励大家大声献上你的赞美！
我们一起唱吧
我站在纷乱之中
我身处混杂之中
还有那些偏离正道的聚集
听啊
我说了！
我说了 要放声高唱 赞美奇妙的耶稣！
He took away my sin.
He took my sin—and my son has only ever seen me singing my song.
Well, as the instruments play,
if you have your own testimony today about how Jesus loved you,
how He saved you,
just lift your voice to Him.
Just take Him.
Oh, thank You, Jesus.
How marvelous, how wonderful is His love.
Praise You, Jesus.
Oh, we praise You.
Oh, we love You because You first loved us.
Should go all the way.
She’s crying.
Hold them in place—he’s falling apart.
Let the wheat say, 'I am small.'
Let the boy say, 'I once knew.'
Because of what the Boy has done, let the weak say, 'I am strong.'
Let the poor say, 'I have.'
because of what the poor have given.
让我们说声感谢吧
因为主为我所赐的
就说“我就这样” 让穷人说“我是 race”
因为主掌管道路 所以说“我祷告” 因为那道边界
让警察说“我是 song”
让穷人说“我是富足的”
因为那“doing”为我们所做的
我当时分心想事情
被一堆杂事和一点情绪低落压得够呛
你有没有过情绪低落的时候？
有个声音对我说 大概是我的良心吧
你咋不感恩呢？
你不是老讲这个吗？
那你为啥不做？
我几周前才刚讲过“凡事都要感恩”
我就说了 你知道吗？
我不想当伪君子
没错
于是我开始感恩
一点感觉都没有
但就在我开始感恩的时候
毕竟我已经好几个小时没为任何事向 God 感恩了
我生命中的一切都开始改变了
我的心、我的头脑 平安涌了进来
我想起 God 是信实的
今天我能跟你说句话吗？
如果你正经历重压
劳苦、网罗 心也分了神
今天不如就向 God 感恩吧！
你们有些人欠的 不是欠 IRS 的
你欠上帝好多没还的感恩 对吧？
欠下的赞美
有多少人欠上帝应得的赞美和感恩？
那我们就来唱这个
我很喜欢这首歌
那是出自 scriptures 的
呃 我们来唱一小段
呃 如果你今天在场 对 Pastor 说：
我也要像你那天那样做
我得现在就开始感恩
可我就是提不起感恩的心情
上帝没说要有任何感觉
祂只说：要感恩
凡事都要感恩
试试看 它会不会彻底翻转你的处境
带着你的心 直接走到前面来 就从这儿上台
如果你正在在线观看
不如现在就站起来
一起在线上献上感恩吧？
我们先从这节经文开始 好吗？
Come on—bring your grateful heart.
Come on.
To the Holy One.
Give thanks.
Because He has given.
Jesus Christ.
Give thanks with a grateful heart.
Give thanks.
To the Holy One.
因他已赐予众人
耶稣哭了
现在举起手来
举起手来 同声宣告
让 wig 说我刚强
让 court 说我已醒
因主所行的大事
让 wig 说我能歌唱
让 court 说我已写下
因为什么呀？
主为我们成就了大事 让我们再唱一遍那节经文吧
或许还有几位弟兄姊妹也上来一起加入我们吧
我们是感恩诗班
阿们 好吗？
我们从这节开始吧
要感谢主！
带着感恩的心来感谢主
来吧 大家都要感恩！
因为他赐给了我们……
He gave us the sun.
It came down with the Great One.
In the fruit of holding fast to the One.
Because He’s given Strong to everyone.
He is the Voice.
Let the wheat say, 'I am sent.' Let the path say, 'I have spoken.' All because of the One.
Let the wheat speak.
Because I am strong.
I am strong.
Let the wings say, 'I am song.'
让贫穷的人宣告：我被高举了
因着主为我们所行的大事
主啊 我们感谢你赐下一切祝福
我们在耶稣里富足
拥有永不消逝的丰盛
我们在耶稣里刚强
不是我们的力量 乃是祂的力量
我们一无所缺
因此我的神必供应我们一切所需
我们为你的平安欢欣
and Your love for us today.
We will cast off every spirit of discouragement and depression.
In the name of Jesus Christ, our Lord.
For the joy of the Lord is our strength today.
And we will rejoice and be glad in it.
Thank You, Lord, for another Sunday when we can praise You,
guide this service, direct it,
and most of all,
Lord, fill this place with Your presence and touch every heart.
Please.
I’m pleading with you
Touch every heart and bless all who are here in Jesus’ name.
I’m so grateful that’s mine.
Oh, the joy—so sweet, so pure—nothing’s better.
I think that’s the dog.
No—nothing’s better.
There’s no one for me.
There’s something better.
Oh, the joy that loves my soul.
Jesus loves me—this I know. Jesus, You are all I need; I know nothing’s better.
Oh, I tried to do it my own way.
And nothing ever changed—until He came with His saving grace.
And took my sins away—the joy
And the peace He’s given me—I’ll just say, there’s nothing better.
There’s nothing better. There’s nothing better.
Because of who You are
I give You praise. Because of who You are, I’ll lay down my life—
and say, 'Lord, I worship You.'
Because of who You are, Lord, I worship You.
因你是谁
因你是谁 荣耀归你
因你是谁 我要赞美你
因你是谁 我要高声颂扬
并说主啊我敬拜你
因你是谁 主啊我敬拜你
因你是谁 耶和华 我的和平的君
我敬拜你 因你是谁
因你是谁 荣耀归你
因你是谁 我要赞美你
Because of who You are, I will lift my voice
and say, 'Lord, I worship You'
Because of who You are, I worship You
Because of who You are, You are so good to me
and I will bless You
Because You see my life, it’s a great thing
So I praise You because of who You are
Because of who You are, I believe You
Because of who You are, I give You praise
Because of who You are, I will lift my voice in worship
因你本为圣 我敬拜你
因我有耶稣 祂的话语常与我同在
我有耶稣 就是你 我的主 就是你 所以我安然
我心回应：阿们
谁看见我的破碎 又将我温柔托起
当我软弱时 耶稣为我承担
又是谁平静风浪？
我被淹没 说不出话
是的 耶稣 就是你 背负我的罪
又是谁将我的心珍藏在祂怀中
还有谁承接我的思绪
并将它们挂上你的臂膀——耶稣 就是你
是的 我的耶稣啊
始终是你啊 Jesus 你明白的
把它践行到底 如同你的祷告一般
哦 我献上我的身体 一生的每一天 都将我的一切交托给你
连同我的一切——这唯独是献上的祭
我们并非凭肉身领受 但啊
今天 我们岂不正需要你献上吗？
对了 我们正在操练呢
我们不只要帮助路易斯安那州的一所监狱
就是安哥拉监狱 我们要给他们送上圣诞礼包
里面有除臭剂、牙刷、牙膏、肥皂 还有一双袜子
不只这所监狱
可能还会帮另一所监狱 那儿有……一千四百名囚犯？
一千八百名
所以我们想用上帝赐给我们的钱去帮助别人 走出去服侍
还得付账单、做维修
主啊 我忘了提奉献的事
但你晓得我们需要什么
Jesus 求你提醒大家奉献
愿有能力献上特别奉献的人
也求你触动那些尚未持续奉献的人
求你感动他们
并激励他们将自己所有的献给主的圣工
因为你已将一切赐给了我们
无论人们离场还是在线奉献 求你祝福这些奉献
奉 Jesus 的名
阿们
两千年前 Jesus 为世人舍命
并从死里复活了
他差遣门徒出去传扬这好消息
什么好消息？
Gospel 就是“好消息”的意思
这好消息就是 God 爱我们
尽管我们犯了罪
就是 God 所说的罪 那些祂看为错的事
这些都记在 His Word 里
我们都犯了罪
去告诉他们 即使他们犯了罪
God has made a way for us to be restored into fellowship with Him.
through the death of His Son.
He removed our guilt and broke down the barrier through His work on the cross—and rose again.
so now we can fellowship with the Lord
and become part of His family.
That’s the good news.
and go to heaven when life is over.
And that’s part of the message.
Uh, this life passes away
but eternity is coming.
And by the way, everyone’s going to spend
everyone here looking at me
you’re all going to spend eternity somewhere.
十亿年之后呢？
时间将不复存在
但让我们好好使用时间
十亿年之后
我们都会在某个地方
永远与主同在 或永远远离
那么 当他们出去开始传道时
他们的听众几乎全是犹太人 因为他们是从 Jerusalem 开始传道的
所有使徒都是犹太人 Jesus 也是犹太人
所以他们向犹太人传讲
事实上 Roman Empire 最初认为 Christianity 是一个衍生教派
是 Judaism 里的一个小教派
呃 因为他们持守《Old Testament》的经文
但现在我们宣告 Messiah 已经来了
因此 当他们四处传讲时
结果不是被拒绝 就是被接受
早期教会全是犹太人
后来外邦人也开始加入了
但后来使徒 Paul
和其他人开始外出传教
他最早的一次传教之旅——其实是第二次——
他最后去了我们叫 Turkey 的地方 当时他们称那里为 Asia
能给我一张纸巾吗？谢谢
呃 真的太感谢了
呃 而且传得比那还远
Paul 去了 Greece
Now all these places were part of the Roman Empire.
Jerusalem, Israel, Palestine—everywhere you went, even Turkey, which they called Asia,
everything was part of this mammoth empire—the largest the world had seen up to that point.
Bigger than the Assyrian Empire, bigger than the Babylonian Empire,
bigger than the Greek Empire under Alexander the Great.
And here was the Roman Empire
which had replaced all of them.
So wherever they went,
they entered a Greek-speaking world,
though in some places, people spoke Latin.
and they began spreading the gospel.
But now their audience was completely different.
Because now people were saying, “Jesus—who?”
What a sin.
How could you even say immorality was wrong?
when in Rome, in the Roman Empire,
husbands would keep their mistresses in the same house as their wives and children.
Saying immorality was wrong was like saying coffee was wrong.
And Greek thought and Greek philosophy
and Greek values had permeated the Roman Empire.
So even though it was the Roman Empire,
it was really, um, Grecianized—
Hellenized—that’s the word.
And in Greek culture, what mattered was—
education, philosophy, and orators.
Some of the biggest names in the Roman Empire were orators—some poets, but especially orators.
And if you could speak before the Senate,
or draw a crowd,
and use ornate language—and your, uh, your speaking ability—to dazzle the crowd,
you were a great person.
Athletes.
Athletes were great.
Because of the Greek Olympic Games they started—
were still held in the Roman Empire.
Wealth.
If you had a lot of money
you were, like, in our culture—
you were considered special.
Why?
Because he made a lot of money.
但如果他是个——呃——呃——特别糟糕的人呢？
无所谓
他赚大钱了
那他就很牛
或者他上电视了
或者她上过大银幕
所以当福音临到那群听众时
那就另当别论了
犹太人争论：他要么就是《Old Testament》应许的弥赛亚
要么他不是弥赛亚
如果他真是弥赛亚
我就信他
还会成为 Christian
使徒 Paul 是早期教会最激烈的迫害者之一
他起初是大数的 Saul
还迫害教会
把人关进监狱 拆散家庭
甚至可能有人因他而死
但后来主向他显现
从此成了热忱的 Christian 和传道者
他正是那位进入罗马帝国各地的人
他向那些拜偶像的人说话
希腊——呃 希腊宗教把将近一万个神带进了罗马帝国
他们有上万个神 拜树、拜山
还有完整的偶像与诸神等级
所以当你说起那位差儿子来到世上的独一真神时 他们简直——
你是在开玩笑吧？
这是开玩笑吗？
这真是开玩笑吗？
所以犹太听众一听这话就难以接受：
传道者竟说
你们错过了弥赛亚
他来了 你们居然错过了他
他就站在你们眼前
你们却完全没意识到
但在罗马帝国的希腊人听来
这简直成了笑谈
等等 你不是在开玩笑吧？
所以你是说 上帝
那位真神、唯一的 God
差遣了他那被钉死在十字架上的儿子
他任凭士兵把他钉上十字架
他流了血 他们还给他戴上荆棘冠
你说那个半裸挂在十字架上的
就是你拜的 God？
得了吧
我说 现实点
那些出去传道的人
罗马帝国还笑话这个
他们早就听惯了那些雄辩家
你在胡说什么呢？
这家伙就是个打鱼的
那些皈依的人
教会里几乎全是刚皈依的奴隶
他们本就占了人口的大多数
可他们嘛……说白了就是最底层的人
全是奴隶
你们手下尽是些奴隶
你们连个像样的地方都没有
你们又不在大楼里聚会
反倒是在家里跟一堆平民百姓聚会
那些大咖在哪儿？
有钱的主儿又在哪儿？
哲学家呢？
我听说有个叫大数的 Saul、使徒 Paul 的人传过道
他啥也不是
他又不是什么雄辩家
我们有真家伙 货真价实
我们有哲学
We’ve got wisdom.
Greek—uh—appreciation of wisdom.
Um, it got into the Roman Empire, and they were just like, oh—
He’s a philosopher.
He’s so wise.
What a communicator.
You know that story about that old Greek speaker named
I think it was Herodotus
who learned to speak perfectly by putting pebbles
gravel into his mouth.
他每天都会嘴里含着小石子练上好几个钟头
等你把石子吐出来
呃……他说话反而更清楚了
舌头也更听使唤了
对了 这事儿我是听以前常来我们教会的一个人说的
他是个电台 DJ
那是很多年前了
他还跟我说
录节目什么的之前
拿支铅笔 呃——
and put it in your mouth, Pastor Simba—you know, just like that—and talk.
Recite Psalm 23 or just talk—with the pencil in your mouth.
Because your tongue’s wrestling with the pencil, right?
Try to say it: 'The Lord is my shepherd...'
'I shall not want,' right?
With the pencil still in there.
And when you take the pencil out,
your tongue doesn’t feel, like, heavy
it’s not, like, sluggish
it’s more alert.
我真不知道干嘛要跟你说这个故事
这跟我讲的完全没关系
我有时候会钻进兔子洞里
所以啊 不管怎样 那就是他们传 gospel 时的问题
就像我们今天文化里的那样
得了吧
你——你懂的
你就是在说 呃 Jesus 是我全部所需
所以你谈的是个你从没见过的隐形人
他就是你全部所需
You don’t need money.
You don’t need a house.
Come on, get real, would you?
That’s our culture, right?
We’re talking about things—why, Pastor?
People have actually said this to me.
I visited your church.
The woman next to me was lifting her hands.
You didn’t tell anyone to lift their hands.
Why was she lifting her hands?
我不懂那是什么意思
我看到 你看 她在哭
但她不难过
她明明很开心 却在哭
里面发生什么事了？
有多少人懂我在说什么？
他们完全听不懂
你到底在说什么啊？
还有这种宗教 唉
哦 所以他还要再回来 然后呢？
我们总有一天都会去 heaven 之类的
拜托 别这么不切实际行吗？
只有你能探究的东西才真实存在
科学方法界定什么是现实
只要你看得见
拿显微镜看都行 或者随便什么方法
那才算真的
别扯什么没人看得见的另一个世界
这简直是胡扯
这就是你控制人的手段 靠什么 pie in the sky 之类的
还有那些乱七八糟的
所以早期教会一走出去 面对的就是这些
Paul 去了希腊南部 Achaea 地区的一座城市
在那里 他去了 Corinth 城并传道
他在那里待了 18 个月
并建立了教会
后来他给那教会写了两封信
因为出现了问题
所以当时对他的指控之一——也是对 Christians 的指控——就是
教会当时面对的问题就是：“喂喂 老兄——”
这简直是个笑话
你说的这事儿 纯属笑话
那些大演说家呢？
钱呢？
那些排场呢？
那些博士呢？
我们要找的是博士
可不是什么渔民和奴隶
这算哪门子低等宗教？
That’s what they’re up against
and we’re still facing it today.
So Paul’s telling them, look—
when I was with you and preaching,
I had wisdom.
They’re laughing at you
but don’t you see?
The world’s wisdom is a joke to God.
Everything people call wise and great—
God just looks at it and goes—
你完全没抓住重点
我们所传的智慧 才是真智慧
但他们就是不懂
换句话说 基督徒并不愚昧
在神看来 基督徒才是世上唯一有智慧的人
于是他接着这个思路说下去
他说：无论我们做什么
却在成熟的人——就是属灵的人——当中传讲智慧
但不是这世代的智慧——Joy 请把这个举高一点
也不是这世代那些注定要灭亡的统治者的智慧
我们是不是该稍微想想这句话？
他说：“我们有一种智慧
但这不是这个时代的智慧
因为这个时代终将过去 ”
他说 我们讲的是另一种智慧 不属于这个时代
也不属于那些终将化为乌有的统治者
所有大人物、所有大政客
所有掌权者、宫殿
联合国、亿万富翁
还有所有那些所谓“成功”的人
他们终将一事无成
到头来 他们什么都不是
因为当上帝回来、打开那些书卷时
他们会发现自己才是最大的输家
他们活在一场幻觉里
哦 他们还以为基督徒活在幻想里
他们会发现 自己一生都在为不重要的事奔波
他们一死 就什么都没了
但我们基督徒 死后
就回家了
How many of you are planning to go home?
We’re going home.
So, do you feel the tension here?
The wisdom of this world and of its rulers.
And he adds—hey,
they’re coming to nothing.
I know, but she’s the biggest movie star.
Everyone wants to be like her.
She’s an influencer.
You people talk—they follow influencers.
你为什么不让 God 和《Bible》来影响你呢？
我们能不能一起说 amen 来回应这句话？
而不是去跟一个连人生是怎么回事都不懂的 influencer
这真让人难过
连去 churches 的 Christians 都
在跟一些到头来什么都不是的人
听懂了吗？
他们到头来什么都不是
不是我说的
是 God 的话说的
那么
不 我们传讲的是上帝的智慧
一个奥秘
谁是这奥秘？
Jesus
这一直被隐藏
是上帝在万世以前为我们的荣耀所预定的
所以说 基督徒有一种智慧
但这智慧是个奥秘
表面看不出来
这不在科学方法的范畴之内
这奥秘就是基督、救恩、上帝的爱和救赎
天堂
成为重生之人
那才是一种真正的智慧
他说 这才是真正的智慧
这才是真正要紧的智慧
弟兄姊妹们 别被那些看起来很有学问的人吓住
他们也没那么神
相信我 他们也就那样
Actually, some of the smartest people
it’s crazy how messed up their lives are
and they don’t even have a—
I was—wait, who’s that?
The—the one who was a Supreme Court Justice
or someone who just got named Secretary of Health or whatever.
One of the questions they got was
Can you define what a woman is?
They couldn’t even define what a woman—
but they’re supposed to be really smart.
PhD.
They’re gonna help run our country.
They can’t even say what a woman is—unlike a man, unlike a woman,
’Cause of all that other stuff, right?
So in thinking they’re wise, they become fools.
So he goes on to say none of this age’s rulers understood it
—that wisdom: Jesus.
Because if they had,
they wouldn’t have crucified the Lord of glory.
All these brilliant folks in the Jewish religion—with their high IQs and religious training.
And don’t forget the Gentiles—with all their learning,
their Greek philosophy, their letters,
their arts—and everything they knew.
They had no idea—none at all.
When God’s own Son came,
He was standing right before them.
They didn’t even get it.
So how smart could you really be?
God Himself was standing right before you,
the Creator of the universe.
可你却没反应过来
但你其实挺机灵的
你真的很聪明
所以 Paul 在这里勉励信徒们
说有一种隐藏的智慧
一种属灵的智慧 没人能明白
世上若没有圣灵的帮助 没人能明白
这正是这段经文我想让你们记住的重点
他说他们没明白
如果他们真有智慧
他们早该明白 这就是上帝
那这个呢？
我总有一天会死
你不觉得我该为死亡做点准备吗？
不不 我就当自己能活 forever
现在有个新晋亿万富翁 说他正在接受治疗
还 somehow 躲在个茧里过日子
还有人向他保证 他能活到 180 岁
不 我刚看到关于他的消息
对了 他长得挺怪的
这家伙长得真怪
他还能活到 180 岁
那又怎样？
那你死了
然后呢？
不 我不想琢磨这个
这算聪明吗？
假装自己永远不会死 这聪明吗？
但这在知识圈里很常见
别提死和税 这两样都别说
Paul now wraps up his thought by saying this.
But now he’s quoting Isaiah 64:4: 'However...'
as it is written:
what no eye has seen,
what no ear has heard,
and what no human mind has ever conceived,
the things God has prepared for those who love Him.
These are the things God has revealed to us by His Spirit.
The Spirit searches all things, even the deep things of God.
Oh, go back.
Verse 9.
Go back.
But as it’s written in the Old Testament,
what no eye has seen,
no scientific method can touch it.
Are you really educated today?
You won’t get a clue just by thinking.
You can go to the library and study,
you’ll never get it.
You can be very rich
You’ll never understand it.
You could be dirt poor.
No eye has seen,
no ear has heard.
what no human mind has ever imagined.
God’s truths are beyond the reach of the human mind.
Not without help.
But what God has prepared
Uh, when I was a kid
我一直以为这句话的意思 就是神为爱他的人所预备的
就是指天堂和天上的一切
但其实不是这个意思
听好了 接着说
这些是神借着他的灵启示给我们的
圣灵——这节经文非常奥秘
圣灵参透万事 甚至神深奥的事也了如指掌
一切属神、能改变你和我生命的事
不只是得救 更是属灵的成长 以及被神使用
唯有圣灵才能启示出来
这叫启示 是圣灵向人内心所启示的
这就是启示 由圣灵启示而来
圣灵究竟是谁？
是祂 不是“它” 是耶稣差来的那位
在祂完成使命并升天之后
祂说：“我要差另一位保惠师来代替我 ”
祂在某些方面会比我更有果效
我被局限在一个身体里
祂却无处不在
我一直与你们同在
他将活在你里面
我教过你们许多道理
但你们始终没真正领会
直到最后一刻
你们还在争谁最大
但他将从内到外更新你们
没有圣灵
人就不会为罪自责
这些新成员中 每个自称信主的人
不过是挂名的信徒
因为圣灵的职事